<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cryspen</title>
    <link>https://cryspen.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cryspen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cryspen.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three (thousand) may keep a secret</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-introduction/</guid>
      <description>“Three may keep a secret, if two of them are dead.” - Benjamin Franklin (1735)
However skeptical we may be of our human ability to keep secrets, we still routinely participate in group conversations that we would like to keep away from prying eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLS - RFC 9420</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-rfc-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-rfc-announcement/</guid>
      <description>✨ We are thrilled to announce the release of the MLS specification as RFC 9420.
RFC 9420 is a comprehensive description of the first standardised, efficient, asynchronous, key establishment protocol with forward secrecy and post-compromise security for groups in size ranging from two to thousands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Jonas</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_jonas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_jonas/</guid>
      <description>📢 Exciting News! 🚀 We are thrilled to welcome Dr. Jonas Schneider-Bensch, to the Cryspen family as our newest R&amp;amp;D Cryptography Engineer!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryspen @ RWC 2023</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/rwc-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/rwc-2023/</guid>
      <description>At Real World Crypto 2023 in Tokyo, we gave a talk on the hacspec language, the hax tool, and the libcrux crypto library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Cryspen</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen was founded in December 2021 by Franziskus Kiefer, Karthikeyan Bhargavan, and Jonathan Protzenko, with the goal of adapting and extending cutting-edge formal verification tools developed at research labs like Inria and applying them to commercial software development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Cryptographic Implementations</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/advanced-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/advanced-crypto/</guid>
      <description>TBD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HACL</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/hacl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/hacl/</guid>
      <description>HACL is a set of formally verified cryptographic libraries in C, JavaScript, OCaml, and Rust. The libraries are based on the HACL* research project, originally developed by Inria and Microsoft Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hacspec</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/hacspec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/hacspec/</guid>
      <description>hacspec is a language and framework for writing succinct, executable, formally verifiable specifications for cryptographic components.
Syntactically, hacspec is a purely functional subset of Rust that aims to be readable by developers, cryptographers, and verification experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Assurance Software Toolchain</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/circus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/circus/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen collaborates with the Prosecco team at Inria to develop a usable, robust, development environment and verification toolchain for security critical software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we Work</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/work/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen is a boutique development and consulting studio focused on bringing state-of-the-art privacy and cryptography solutions to customers, using cutting-edge formal methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPKE</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/hpke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/hpke/</guid>
      <description>HPKE is scheme provides a variant of public-key encryption of arbitrary-sized plaintexts for a recipient public key. It includes three authenticated variants, including one which authenticates possession of a pre-shared key, and two optional ones which authenticate possession of a KEM private key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/imprint/</guid>
      <description>Company Name: Cryspen Sarl
Registered Office: 149 Avenue du Maine, 75014 Paris, France
Email: info@cryspen.com
Managing Director: Franziskus Kiefer
Registration Number: 908 684 848 R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/jobs/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenMLS</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/openmls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/openmls/</guid>
      <description>Messaging Layer Security (MLS) is a security layer for end-to-end encrypting communication in large dynamic groups. It is being specified by the IETF MLS working group and designed to be efficient, practical and secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Quantum Transition</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/pq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/pq/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of post-quantum cryptography, every organization will be expected to upgrade their systems, protocols and infrastructure to be post-quantum ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Group Communication</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/mls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/mls/</guid>
      <description>With new regulations like the Digital Market Act, companies now have to embrace interoperability, especially when it comes to communications and messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verify your Security</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/prove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/prove/</guid>
      <description>Security protocols and constructions are pervasive. Some are well-known, like TLS; but your organization may be using custom security mechanisms for identity management, key propagation, secure storage… Having complete confidence in such a design requires an in-depth security analysis that covers side-channels, cryptographic design, and software design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HACL Packages v0.6</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hacl-0_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hacl-0_6/</guid>
      <description>Today, we announce the first release of the HACL Packages libraries. 🎉
This release of HACL packages includes the first release of the HACL C library and a new release of the hacl-star OCaml bindings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenMLS</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hello-openmls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hello-openmls/</guid>
      <description>We have joined forces with our friends from Phoenix R&amp;amp;D to improve OpenMLS.
The MLS protocol draft is in the IETF working group&amp;rsquo;s last call and is thus on track to become an RFC soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HACL Packages</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/introducing-hacl-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/introducing-hacl-packages/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, Tezos and Nomadic Labs started to work with Cryspen to improve HACL* and ensure that it is a viable long-term solution for Tezos&#39; cryptographic needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is High Assurance Cryptography?</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/high-assurance-cryptography-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/high-assurance-cryptography-1/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen builds high assurance cryptography. But what does this actually mean?
Before focusing on cryptography it is interesting to look at high assurance software in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Executable HPKE Specification</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hpke_spec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hpke_spec/</guid>
      <description>HPKE, published as RFC 9180, describes a scheme for hybrid public key encryption.
📚 Please go and read our TL;DR on HPKE if you nee more background on HPKE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TL;DR - Hybrid Public Key Encryption</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/tldr-hpke/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/tldr-hpke/</guid>
      <description>HPKE, defined in RFC 9180, is a CFRG standard that describes a scheme for hybrid public key encryption. It is co-authored by my Cryspen co-founder Karthikeyan Bhargavan and one of his PhD students Benjamin Lipp as part of his research at Inria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryspen ERC PoC Grant</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/erc-poc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/erc-poc/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen co-founder Karthik Bhargavan got awarded an ERC Proof of Concept grant for commercialising the know-how and landmark research results from his Inria research group PROSECCO through Cryspen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
