<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cryspen</title>
    <link>https://cryspen.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cryspen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cryspen.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Formally Verified Post-Quantum Cryptography</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/fospqc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/fospqc/</guid>
      <description>The US National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) just released the first three standards for Post-Quantum KEMs (ML-KEM) and Signatures (ML-DSA, SLH-DSA).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the hax Playground</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/announcement-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/announcement-playground/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re proud to announce the hax playground! Inspired by the Rust Playground, the hax playground allows you to play with hax directly in your web browser!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryspen Welcomes Maxime</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_maxime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_maxime/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to announce that Maxime Buyse has joined the Cryspen team as a Formal Verification Engineer! 🎉&#xA;Maxime is a whiz when it comes to formal methods, software verification, compilers, and functional programming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Assurance IoT PQC</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/pqc-iot-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/pqc-iot-announce/</guid>
      <description>Together with our sister-company CryptoEng, we extend our libcrux cryptographic library with support for resource constrained IoT devices. Read their announcement here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryspen @ FMCP 2024</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/fmcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/fmcp/</guid>
      <description>The US National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) publishes a number of important cryptographic standards (including upcoming ones for post-quantum cryptography), and runs the cryptographic algorithm and module validation programs that validate and issue certificates to cryptographic libraries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking New Possibilities</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hax-sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hax-sandbox/</guid>
      <description>We have been developing the hax toolchain over the last two years, in collaboration with research teams at Inria and the University of Aarhus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Quantum TLS in Bertie</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/pq-bertie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/pq-bertie/</guid>
      <description>The prospect of quantum computers breaking most public key encryption in use today has created the need for new schemes that can resist classical and potential quantum attackers alike.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptographic protocol verification with hax</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hax-pv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hax-pv/</guid>
      <description>This blog post details an example of how to use our hax toolchain for verifying the security of cryptographic protocol implementations written in Rust.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conference Talks</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/rwc2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/rwc2024/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen attended a number of conference in April and March. Here is a list of all slides and videos.&#xA;We will update links when more resources become available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Quantum OpenMLS</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/pq-openmls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/pq-openmls/</guid>
      <description>OpenMLS now offers security against harvest-now-decrypt-later (HNDL) quantum adversaries.&#xA;In #1546 we merged support for the X-Wing KEM draft, which is an early draft for securely combining elliptic-curve-based Diffie-Hellman with ML-KEM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Quantum Group Messaging</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/pq-mls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/pq-mls/</guid>
      <description>With multiple post-quantum cryptographic algorithms (ML-KEM, ML-DSA) nearing standardization, enterprises, research groups, and standards bodies have started investigating what post-quantum secure protocols should look like and what properties they should satisfy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verifying Libcrux&#39;s ML-KEM</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/ml-kem-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/ml-kem-verification/</guid>
      <description>In a recent blog post, we described Cryspen&amp;rsquo;s new Rust implementation of ML-KEM in Rust, and talked about how our high-assurance development methodology helped us find a new timing bug in various other Kyber implementations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verified ML-KEM (Kyber) in Rust</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/ml-kem-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/ml-kem-implementation/</guid>
      <description>ML-KEM, previously known as Kyber, is the first post-quantum secure key-encapsulation mechanism (KEM) to get standardised by NIST in FIPS 203.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Jan &amp; Lucas</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_jan_lucas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_jan_lucas/</guid>
      <description>📢 Exciting News! Cryspen is thrilled to announce the addition of two exceptional minds to our team: Dr. Lucas Franceschino and Jan Winkelmann.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of Signal&#39;s PQXDH</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/pqxdh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/pqxdh/</guid>
      <description>Signal recently published a new, post-quantum secure, version of their X3DH protocol called PQXDH. As with any new cryptographic protocol, it is important to precisely analyse its security properties, especially for something as important as Signal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Campus Cyber Circus Project</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/cyber-campus-hax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/cyber-campus-hax/</guid>
      <description>🎉 We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that Cryspen partnered with Inria on a transfer project to build a new integrated development and verification environment (IDVE).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specifying Oblivious Pseudonymization</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/scrambledb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/scrambledb/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we announce an executable specification in the hacspec specification language for the ScrambleDB pseudonymization system, developed by Cryspen as part of the BMBF ATLAS project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Defense Prize 2023</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/internet-defense-prize-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/internet-defense-prize-2023/</guid>
      <description>At the 32nd Usenix Security Symposium in Anaheim CA, a paper on the Messaging Layer Security Protocol, co-authored by our founders Jonathan Protzenko and Karthikeyan Bhargavan, was awarded both the Distinguished Paper Award and the prestigious Internet Defense Prize.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prairie and Atlas</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/prarie-and-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/prarie-and-atlas/</guid>
      <description>With the widespread adoption and deployment of machine learning across enterprises, ever-increasing amounts of data are being collected, stored, communicated, combined, and computed over by sophisticated algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three (thousand) may keep a secret</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-introduction/</guid>
      <description>“Three may keep a secret, if two of them are dead.” - Benjamin Franklin (1735)&#xA;However skeptical we may be of our human ability to keep secrets, we still routinely participate in group conversations that we would like to keep away from prying eyes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLS - RFC 9420</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-rfc-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-rfc-announcement/</guid>
      <description>✨ We are thrilled to announce the release of the MLS specification as RFC 9420.&#xA;RFC 9420 is a comprehensive description of the first standardised, efficient, asynchronous, key establishment protocol with forward secrecy and post-compromise security for groups in size ranging from two to thousands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Jonas</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_jonas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/welcome_jonas/</guid>
      <description>📢 Exciting News! 🚀 We are thrilled to welcome Dr. Jonas Schneider-Bensch, to the Cryspen family as our newest R&amp;amp;D Cryptography Engineer!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryspen @ RWC 2023</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/rwc-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/rwc-2023/</guid>
      <description>At Real World Crypto 2023 in Tokyo, we gave a talk on the hacspec language, the hax tool, and the libcrux crypto library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HACL Packages v0.6</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hacl-0_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hacl-0_6/</guid>
      <description>Today, we announce the first release of the HACL Packages libraries. 🎉&#xA;This release of HACL packages includes the first release of the HACL C library and a new release of the hacl-star OCaml bindings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenMLS</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hello-openmls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hello-openmls/</guid>
      <description>We have joined forces with our friends from Phoenix R&amp;amp;D to improve OpenMLS.&#xA;The MLS protocol draft is in the IETF working group&amp;rsquo;s last call and is thus on track to become an RFC soon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HACL Packages</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/introducing-hacl-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/introducing-hacl-packages/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, Tezos and Nomadic Labs started to work with Cryspen to improve HACL* and ensure that it is a viable long-term solution for Tezos&#39; cryptographic needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is High Assurance Cryptography?</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/high-assurance-cryptography-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/high-assurance-cryptography-1/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen builds high assurance cryptography. But what does this actually mean?&#xA;Before focusing on cryptography it is interesting to look at high assurance software in general.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Executable HPKE Specification</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/hpke_spec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/hpke_spec/</guid>
      <description>HPKE, published as RFC 9180, describes a scheme for hybrid public key encryption.&#xA;📚 Read our TL;DR on HPKE if you need more background on HPKE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TL;DR - Hybrid Public Key Encryption</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/tldr-hpke/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/tldr-hpke/</guid>
      <description>HPKE, defined in RFC 9180, is a CFRG standard that describes a scheme for hybrid public key encryption. It is co-authored by my Cryspen co-founder Karthikeyan Bhargavan and one of his PhD students Benjamin Lipp as part of his research at Inria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryspen ERC PoC Grant</title>
      <link>https://cryspen.com/post/erc-poc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cryspen.com/post/erc-poc/</guid>
      <description>Cryspen co-founder Karthik Bhargavan got awarded an ERC Proof of Concept grant for commercialising the know-how and landmark research results from his Inria research group PROSECCO through Cryspen.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
