<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RFC on Cryspen</title><link>https://cryspen.com/tags/rfc/</link><description>Recent content in RFC on Cryspen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cryspen.com/tags/rfc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MLS Group State Forks: What, Why, How</title><link>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-fork-resolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-fork-resolution/</guid><description>&lt;p>Group state forks are faulty states that MLS groups can end up in. This article looks at what they are exactly, how that happens and how to resolve them. We also look at a new OpenMLS feature that makes fork resolutions a little easier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three (thousand) may keep a secret</title><link>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>“Three may keep a secret, if two of them are dead.”&lt;/em> - Benjamin Franklin (1735)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>However skeptical we may be of our human ability to keep secrets, we still routinely participate in group conversations that we would like to keep away from prying eyes. We exchange confidential work emails through corporate mail servers, discuss project internals on private Slacks, and exchange deeply personal information with family and friends on WhatsApp groups. The loss of this private data to malicious outsiders can result in public embarrassment, financial loss, and for vulnerable persons like journalists or activists, even threats to life and liberty.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MLS - RFC 9420</title><link>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-rfc-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cryspen.com/post/mls-rfc-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>✨ We are thrilled to announce the release of the MLS specification as &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc9420">RFC 9420&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc9420">RFC 9420&lt;/a> is a comprehensive description of the first standardised, efficient, asynchronous, key establishment protocol with forward secrecy and post-compromise security for groups in size ranging from two to thousands. While Cryspen didn&amp;rsquo;t exist back when the MLS working group was established, our co-founder Karthik played a pivotal role in designing MLS from the beginning by contributing to the original design of &lt;a href="https://inria.hal.science/hal-02425247/file/treekem+(1).pdf">TreeKEM&lt;/a>, the basis of MLS today.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>